

SARISH BOBBAN

PERSONAL

Date of Birth : 09.12.1975 **Passport No.** : \$9741355

Address : Mahooz, Block 333

Phone No. : +973 34481007

E-mail : sarishariyannur@gmail.com
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/sarish-

QUALIFICATIONS

VELLORE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

MBA specialized in Marketing Vellore | 63%

MEGA DIGITAL MARKETING

2022

CALICUT UNIVERSITY

bobban-5b833239/

B.Sc. Chemistry on main 59.5

CALICUT UNIVERSITY

Pre Degree (12th) 59.5%

SSLC

69%

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH : FLUENT INDIAN : FLUENT MALAYALAM : FLUENT TAMIL : FLUENT

SUMMARY

Experienced Product Manager with over 21 years' experience in International and Indian market. Proven ability to handle country or independent branch operations, introduce new products in market and network development through marketing, training and partner relationships. Looking for similar challenging position in reputed organizations. More than 16 years' experience in Lubricants and 5 years in consumer durable products.

EXPERIENCES

GULF OIL MIDDLE EAST, UAE | 2019 - 2022 SALES MANAGER

Responsible for Bahrain Market for GULF OIL brand Lubricant. Average yearly volume achieved 700 KL.

UDRIVE BAHRAIN, TLB DIVISION | 2016 – 2019 ASSISTANT MANAGER

Overlooking Bahrain Market for SERVO brand Lubricants. Achieved sales volume of 500 KL per year.

AL MANA ENTERPRISES CO. BAHRAIN | 2011 – 2016 (S.H. ALMANA QATAR) - ASSISTANT MANAGER

Handling Bahrain Market for SERVO brand Lubricants and successfully introduced SERVO brand Lubricants in this market. Achieved sales volume of 300 KL per year.

Gulf Oil Corporation Limited | INDIA 2005 – 2010 TERRITORY BUSINESS MANAGER

Responsible for promoting GULF OIL brand Lubricants in Kerala and South Tamilnadu. Average sales achieved was 1200 KL per year.

V-GUARD INDUSTRIES LTD | INDIA 2000 – 2005 MARKETING OFFICER

Responsible for handling multiple distributors across Kerala for House wiring cables, Pumps, Electronic Stabilizers, Water heaters, PVC Pipes.

CANON PHOTOCOPIERS | INDIA 1999 – 2000

Market research executive

SARISH BOBBAN

KEY SKLILLS

- Develop and implement, Sales and Marketing strategies for the division and monitor the performance of the division accordingly.
- In depth product knowledge in Lubricant chemistry for Automobile, Industrial and Marine segments.
- Network development, Brand promotion, Brand visibility in given territory.
- Conduct comprehensive market studies, takes all external and internal factors into consideration, identifies strategic actions to be taken (such as introducing products, market campaigns, price, etc).
- Price positioning and profit margins and for the preparation of price lists.
- Target setting for subordinates and monitors their performance accordingly; meets with concerned staff on daily basis to discuss the accomplishment of targets, collection of payments, clients, etc.
- Personally manage important clients and accounts.
- Ensures that Sales Team provide a superior customer service and generate growth of sales by providing routine training.
- Prepares, implements, and supervises development strategies to enhance the caliber of employees, procedures, policies, and systems in a manner that guarantees customer satisfaction and cost efficiency.
- Responsible for the management of inventory and replenishment orders; ensures that an acceptable level
 of stock for necessary products is maintained at all times; approves orders after taking the final approval
 from the after-sales director and finalizing financial formalities.
- Sustains smooth communication channels with principals regarding supplies, prices, payment terms of
 products; ensures the availability of technical support, policies & procedures, work
 instructions, etc.
- Reviewing and approving monthly sales & Damp; inventory reports and the output of the division with a view to
 - increase the efficiency and to reduce the operational cost while maintaining if not increasing the quality levels of the services provided to the dealers and customers; reports to directors accordingly.
- Providing guidance, (technical, administrative, etc.) to subordinates; takes immediate and remedial action during emergencies.
- Ensuring customer care related activities such as conducting customer satisfaction surveys, handling customer complaints, increasing customer awareness, and analyzing customer feedback are prepared by responsible subordinates.
- Digital Marketing skills, designing marketing campaign flyers, Social media marketing, SEO.

OTHER SKILLS

Computer Proficiency : Digital Marketing, Photoshop, MS Office

Personal Strength : Self-motivated & Optimistic.
Languages Known : English, Malayalam, Tamil, Hindi

Reference upon request Thank you